

Dusty is an experienced Linux Administrator with over 10 years of experience in RedHat, ranging from small environments to those with more than one thousand machines, physical(RackSpace) and virtual(Tractor Supply Company). An expert in unusual bash one liners, regular expressions, text manipulation, and some recent experience in Data Mining and Machine Learning, in R and Python.

Technical Skills

RedHat Linux 10+ years	Apache	Bash
Python	R language	Virtualization (VMWare, Xen, KVM)
OpenStack	Cloud (RackSpace,AWS,Linode)	MySQL Administration 7 years
Perl	JavaScript (Front, and Back End)	Development (Agile, MVC)

Work Experience

Contracting/PHS4J Linux Administrator/Developer Present Consulting

Charleston, SC,

July 2015 -

Philadelphia, PA and Nashville, TN

- Maintained over 1000 RedHat systems, physical and vCenter VMs TSC
- Set up thousands of servers using DevOps tools, Ansible
- Set up hosting company using VMWare, KVM, and WHMCMS
- Developed Configuration Management/Virtualization Tool (Python)
- Supported companies such as Linode Inc., and Tractor Supply Company
- Developed a Python tool specifically for use with the Linode API.
- Experience with Machine Learning and DataMining (R language, Python)
- ESXi, XEN, and KVM support
- Developed an OpenSource deployment tool for Esxi, Linode, Docker and Redhat Sat Server

Linux Administrator Rackspace Hosting

August 2014 – July 2015

San Antonio, TX

- Supported customers, and automated alerts, via tickets and phone calls, performing Linux maintenance.
 - Developed a Python tool specifically for use with the Rackspace API.
 - Was responsible for performing Linux maintenance and administration tasks.
 - Installation and configuration of Apache web server, extended base functionality with third-party modules.
 - Troubleshooting Magento setup and installation and caching functionality.
 - Custom Python Development to implement business logic for manual Linux administration tasks.
 - Used OpenStack extensively to manage cloud servers.

Systems Administrator/Web Developer

Freelance Work

September 2013 – August 2014 Nashville, TN

• Worked with a variety of clients in the telecom industry, supporting web development efforts to implement evolving business requirements.



- Developed a telecommunications portal for buying and selling cell phones. Created multiple Wordpress and informational sites. As well as other e-commerce sites.
- Used Django Web Development framework to create databases backed applications, utilized MySQL.
- PHP Development with Propel, an operational/relational database management tool.
- Developed database driven Node is application for online surveys, similar to a tool like Survey Monkey.
- Used jQuery to create interactive and response web user interface for web applications.
- Developed complex backend Perl scripts, utilized ModPerl and CGI.

Developer/Unix Admin

March 2013 – September 2013

Nashville, TN

Horton Group

- Drupal Development and Unix Administration
- Ubuntu Linux servers
- PHP Development with Drupal
- jQuery Development
- Cloud Experience
- Linux Administration

Developer And Unix Admin

April 2012 – July 2012 (contract)

Nashville, TN

- My original contract was for moving sites over, from two different environments, but quickly expanded to PHP(propel) development
- Various Linux Maintenance
- PHP Development with Propel
- jQuery Development

Developer

Ten Fast Feet

January 2012 – October 2012 (contract)

Capital Accounts

- Maintaining a debt collection database and its interface for the call center employees
- RoR Development with MSSQL
- PHP Development PDO and MSSQL and MySQL
- Python Development
- Javascript interface components

Developer

October 2010 – October 2011 (contract)

Mars Petcare

Franklin, TN

- Maintaining and creating new features for FOSwiki
- Perl Development and MySQL
- Maintenance and New Feature creation of several FOSwiki wikis
- Maintained on a windows server
- Javascript Features including ajax and jQuery

Developer

September 2010 - November 2010 (contract)

Music and Books Christian

• Worked on slicehost Linux servers(Ubuntu)

Franklin, Tennessee



- Development of Internal tool involving both the integration of the Volusion API and a 3PL(Third Party Logistics) Application
- PHP Development and MySQL Code Igniter
- Maintenance of Musichristian.com
- Parsing an XML file, and dumping select contents into a MySQL database
- Reading and writing of proprietary format files(CDF-lite), from Ingram Books
- Administration of the MySQL database

Developer/Linux Systems Administrator

November 2008 - August 2010

Dobie Media

- Worked on amazon cloud servers, creating and maintaining (CentOS)
- Heavy Cloud Experience, Experience with High Availability and Scaling
- Development of Perl Sys Admin tools
- Development on the back end of the main Eviesays.com app (Mod_Perl)
- Scraping off other websites for insertion into MySQL Database using Perl scripts
- Setting up and maintaining the apache servers for a highly scalable application (Eviesays)
- Eviesays used MySQL and the Perl DBI, to access the database
- Wore a lot of hats, this is a small startup

Web Developer

Freelance

September 2008 - November 2008

Nashville, Tennessee

- PHP and Perl development of internal web applications
 - Development of Perl And Python clients
 - SEO experience

Network Consultant

December 2007 - September 2008

Dynamic Edge

Nashville, TN/Ann Arbor, MI

- Wide Variety of networking and OS experience, with a focus on 2003 SBS, and Debian Linux
- Perl and PHP web app development
- SEO experience
- As a consultant I interacted with the customer in such a way that I made recommendations and explained complex issues
- Cisco WAN Experience
- Both Postgres and MySQL servers, were used for DE projects

Education

High-Tech Institute

July 2006

Associates of Applied Science

Nashville, TN

Computer Networking and Security Major

Certifications and Awards

- A+ Certified
- Network+ Certified
- Microsoft Certified Professional
- High-Tech Institute Information Technology Award Recipient